<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2019-05-30T12:40:47Z</responseDate>
    <request metadataPrefix="oai_dc" set="adminset:Dissertations" verb="ListRecords"
        >https://ir.lib.unc.edu/catalog/oai</request>
    <ListRecords>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:4x51hj112</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T16:37:41Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Essays on resource flexibilities in services</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Amal Samuel, Adelina Gnanlet</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>Kenan-Flagler Business School</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Gilland, Wendell G.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>December 2007</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Service firms unable to store services, constantly search for
                        strategies to minimize supply-demand imbalance in resources. Escalating
                        costs, nursing shortages, and process inefficiencies have led the US
                        healthcare system to operate at near-full capacity and maintain high
                        utilization levels. Even though hospitals often function at full capacity,
                        they are expected to treat all patients due to legal, social and moral
                        obligations. Hospitals use a combination of resource flexibility strategies
                        to reduce supply-demand imbalance due to demand variability. In this
                        dissertation, we analyze the benefits of using flexibility strategies on
                        critical resources such as labor (nursing staff), equipment (bed spaces),
                        and patient assignment to contain demand variability in the short-term.
                        Staffing flexibility, often referred to as cross-training, is widely used in
                        many service firms to increase labor utilization, morale, and job
                        enrichment. Although cross-training is cost-efficient, cross-trained nurses
                        are less productive in new units. In the first essay, we analyze the cost
                        savings vs. productivity changes when using staffing flexibility in
                        hospitals. We find that productivity of cross-trained nursing staff has a
                        significant effect on the optimal amount of cross-training. There is also an
                        interaction effect between productivity of cross-trained nurses,
                        cross-training cost, and demand variability. In the second essay, we add a
                        second resource flexibility strategy referred to as demand upgrades.
                        Patients who are typically treated in a simple unit can be upgraded to a
                        complex unit when beds are unavailable in the simple unit. We compare the
                        impact of these two resource flexibility strategies on a hospital’s ability
                        to meet stochastic patient demand. We also look at the impact of the timing
                        of capacity and staffing decisions on system performance. In the third
                        essay, we develop a resource flexibility strategy framework that utilizes
                        internal resources (labor, equipment, and patient assignment) to efficiently
                        manage different levels of demand variability. The insights, issues and
                        implications needed for managers to implement flexibility models are also
                        presented in the third essay. Thus, this dissertation has analyzed the
                        benefit, trade-offs, limitations, and outcomes in implementing critical
                        resource flexibility strategies in hospitals to minimize supply-demand
                        imbalance and address short-term demand variability.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/4x51hj112</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:0g354f31b</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T16:37:50Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Communicating About the Rural Advancement Foundation International –
                        USA: An Application of Organizational Identity, Organizational Image, and
                        the Situational Theory of Publics to a Public Relations Plan</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Hermann, Claire</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Media and Journalism</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Boynton, Lois A.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>May 2007</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>This project analyzes RAFI's current communication methods and
                        provides a plan for its communication future. I begin by giving a short
                        overview of RAFI's structure and history to provide context to the
                        discussion. Second, I review literature on organizational identity and
                        segmenting publics that will illuminate the key role that communication
                        plays in defining an organization and helping it connect with stakeholders.
                        Finally, this project develops a public relations campaign to create a
                        coherent and compelling way of communicating about the organization to
                        stakeholders while working within the time and budget constraints of a small
                        organization.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/0g354f31b</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:9s161626c</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T17:42:02Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Courtship and the Making of Marriage in Early Middle English
                        Romance</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Swezey, Margaret F.</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of English and
                        Comparative Literature</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Wittig, Joseph S.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>August 2009</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>The earliest romances in English were especially concerned with
                        questions of courtship and marriage, and explore a variety of issues and
                        themes relating to the making of marriage. This study focuses on three early
                        Middle English romances composed c. 1250-c.1310: Havelok the Dane, King
                        Horn, and Sir Beves of Hamtoun. I employ close readings with careful
                        attention to language and draw on the canon law and historical studies of
                        marriage practices in medieval England to illuminate references to law, the
                        marriage liturgy, and custom in these early romances. These romances not
                        only reflect law and custom, however, but they also sent messages to their
                        audience of rural gentry and urban merchants. Some of these messages
                        reinforce the status quo, such as the ideas that one should marry someone
                        wealthy and socially suitable, that love and free consent to marriage should
                        lead to an appropriate marriage, and the importance of establishing a
                        dynasty. On the other hand, the romances also include subversive messages,
                        depicting strong heroines exercising agency and showing heroes and heroines
                        resisting arranged marriages. Above all, these romances wholeheartedly
                        embrace the consensual theory of marriage, in which only the free consent of
                        the couple is necessary to create a marriage, and consequently promote love
                        matches over arranged marriages and individual choice over larger social
                        pressures.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/9s161626c</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:8p58pd02r</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T17:42:13Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>An Examination of D-serine Augmentation on the Behavioral and Cellular
                        Mechanisms of Cocaine Seeking</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Healey, Kati</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Psychology and
                        Neuroscience</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Reissner, Kathryn</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Giovanello, Kelly</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Carelli, Regina</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Fitting, Sylvia</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Lysle, Donald</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>December 2017</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Withdrawal from chronic cocaine use is characterized by cellular
                        adaptations and structural remodeling within the brain’s reward circuitry,
                        which are believed to drive persistent drug seeking and relapse. In
                        particular, glutamatergic projections onto nucleus accumbens medium spiny
                        neurons (MSNs) exhibit synaptic strengthening but a loss of plasticity in
                        preclinical animal models of cocaine abuse. Recent evidence suggests that
                        levels of D-serine, an astrocyte derived co-agonist of the NDMA receptor,
                        are reduced in the accumbens following withdrawal from chronic
                        non-contingent cocaine exposure, and that administration of D-serine can
                        reverse these synaptic changes. Moreover, we have found that astrocytes in
                        the nucleus accumbens (NAc) core make fewer synaptic connections following
                        cocaine self-administration and extinction, suggesting reduced D-serine tone
                        on NMDA receptors through volume diffusion. Thus, the overarching goal of
                        this dissertation was to investigate the ability of D-serine augmentation to
                        attenuate cocaine seeking following a cocaine plus cue-primed reinstatement
                        event and then to characterize the mechanism by which D-serine augmentation
                        attenuated this cocaine seeking. Using the self-administration and
                        extinction model of cocaine abuse, the present series of experiments found
                        that systemic and intra-accumbal D-serine augmentation attenuated cocaine
                        seeking, and that systemic D-serine augmentation depotentiated the synapse
                        and enhanced NMDA receptor activation in the NAc core. Interestingly, the
                        experiments presented here conclude that there are no changes in surface
                        protein expression of glutamatergic ionotropic subunits from the NMDA and
                        AMPA receptors following D-serine augmentation. Therefore, the experiments
                        were unable to determine the direct mechanism of action by which D-serine
                        augmentation is reducing relapse to cocaine seeking. However, it can be
                        concluded that NMDA receptor induced internalization of AMPA receptors is
                        not likely the mechanism of the D-serine augmentation effect. Together,
                        these data enhance the current understanding of NMDA receptor involvement in
                        cocaine relapse behaviors, such that NMDA receptors oppose reinstatement of
                        cocaine seeking. We also provide a detailed characterization of NMDA and
                        AMPA receptor expression and synaptic function after enhancing the NMDA
                        receptor co-agonist D-serine.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>NMDA Receptor</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Cocaine Seeking</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Neurosciences</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>sciences</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Behavioral</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>D-serine</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/8p58pd02r</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:9s161627n</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T17:42:28Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Re-visioning the Northeast: economic difference and alternative
                        visions of development in the Brazilian semiarid</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Araujo, Ana M.</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Anthropology</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Escobar, Arturo</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2009</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>This dissertation documents the creation, maintenance and
                        existence of practices of economic difference, or non-capitalist practices,
                        among residents of the town of Sobradinho in Northeast Brazil. This project
                        traces residents' placed-based responses to the construction of the
                        Sobradinho hydroelectric dam in the 1970s and the role of state discourse
                        and intervention in shaping both a sense of regional identity and in
                        creating a regional economy for the national economic integration of this
                        underdeveloped region. The São Francisco Valley, where the town is located,
                        has witnessed the rapid proliferation of export-oriented agroindustrial
                        firms since the late 1980s as part of Brazil's economic restructuring. As
                        state development strategies have had differing impacts on men and women
                        (i.e. men were targeted as a mobile labor force, while, more recently, women
                        have been recruited as temporary waged labor in the agro-industry), there
                        has been a consequent shift away from former subsistence agricultural
                        livelihoods to those premised on wage labor. Accordingly, this project
                        examines changing gender relations and the generational aspects of the
                        formation of regional economic subjectivities. Despite the seeming
                        entrenchment of market-oriented economic models, this research indicates
                        that residents continue to support older forms of labor practice and also
                        create new labor models that are not premised upon capitalist labor regimes.
                        In keeping with this, women in the community are also involved in what could
                        be termed the care economy or the community economy. Following feminist
                        geographers Katherine Gibson and Julie Graham's work in reading for
                        difference, this study highlights how residents, rather than becoming
                        market-oriented neoliberal subjects, have engaged in a micropolitics of
                        resubjectivation whereby they nurture and sustain forms of economic practice
                        that are not market-oriented. These projects of reworking economic models
                        are linked with a broader re-visioning of representations of the sertão
                        (backlands) towards one centered on the Brazilian semiarid, focusing on
                        culturally and ecologically appropriate production models. In documenting
                        these projects, this dissertation maps possibilities for alternative forms
                        of development, potentialities for a postdevelopment future, and the
                        creation of alternative economic practices under the processes of neoliberal
                        globalization.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/9s161627n</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:5138jd92m</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T17:42:32Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>The perspectival nature of emergence</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Taylor, Elanor</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Philosophy</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Lange, Marc</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>I examine various attempts to solve this problem of “collapsing
                        emergence” by imposing principled restrictions on the admissible micro-level
                        properties underlying cases of emergence. I argue that such attempts fail
                        and that to solve the problem we must appeal to the connection between
                        emergence and explanation. I argue that we use the concept of emergence to
                        track the availability (or not) of scientific explanations, and that what
                        qualifies as an available explanation differs across different
                        “perspectives”, where a “perspective” is the point of view of a particular
                        observer. This connection between emergence and explanation provides a
                        solution to the collapse problem because, I argue, collapse-inducing
                        properties fail to provide resources for the explanations that emergence
                        tracks, and so cannot render a macro-level property non-emergent. Embracing
                        this solution (and hence the possibility of emergence) involves embracing
                        the idea that emergence is relative to a perspective. Understanding
                        emergence as relative to a perspective is contrary to some popular
                        conceptions of emergence, which take emergence to be a metaphysical,
                        perspective-independent phenomenon. I argue that such conceptions are
                        misguided and that emergence can play a major role in philosophical and
                        scientific enquiry into relationships between properties of parts and wholes
                        and between different levels in nature, but it can do so only as a
                        perspectival phenomenon, rather than a metaphysical one.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Philosophy</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/5138jd92m</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:kk91fk598</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T17:43:00Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Structure analysis of titanate nanotube/organic molecule hybrid and
                        self-healing polymer</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Jia, Yuanyuan</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Physics and
                        Astronomy</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Wu, Yue</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2007</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>In this dissertation I report the structure and property
                        characterization of two kinds of materials on the micro- and nano-scale
                        level, the self-healing polymer Surlyn and a titanate nanotube/organic
                        molecule hybrid. Multiple techniques have been utilized to study the
                        structural, dynamic, thermal, and optical properties of the materials. In
                        the first study, the thermal, structural, and dynamic properties of the
                        self-healing polymer Surlyn (poly(ethylene-co-methacrylic acid) polymer
                        neutralized with Na+) were investigated. By introducing a suitable cation,
                        Na+ e.g., Surlyn possesses unique properties, such as the intriguing
                        property of self-healing. Understanding the role of the cations in the
                        material, the chemical structure and the physical properties of the polymer
                        is crucial for potential applications. The thermal property of Surlyn is
                        characterized by differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) and microscopic
                        structures are studied by NMR. It is found that although thermal properties
                        change significantly, the structure and dynamics of ionic aggregates
                        (consisting of Na+-O- pairs) remain unchanged under aging and mechanical
                        deformation. The distance between Na+ ions was also estimated. In the second
                        study titanate nanotubes were successfully synthesized. Titanate nanotubes
                        have great potential for applications in photocatalysis due to their unique
                        structural and photocatalytic properties. However, their wide band gap, 3.7
                        eV, and the Ti defect sites present problems for the photovoltaic
                        applications Surface modification, e.g. attachment of charge-transfer
                        ligands, is one of the most effective approaches to modify the optical
                        absorption spectrum and restore the sixfold coordination of Ti sites. In
                        order to study the mechanisms of bonding between titanate nanotubes and the
                        charge transfer ligands, I chose three different molecules, hydroquinone,
                        4-methoxypenol(MEHQ) and catechol. Each of these three molecules is expected
                        to form different bonding configuration. The optical and structural
                        properties of titanate nanotubes and the three hybrid structures (titanate
                        nanotube/hydroquinone, titanate nanotube/MEHQ and titanate
                        nanotube/catechol) are characterized by multiple techniques, such as UV-vis,
                        Raman spectroscopy, X-ray diffraction and NMR spectroscopy, etc. It is found
                        that by forming a bidentate structure, organic molecules (hydroquinone and
                        catechol) and titanate nanotubes can form hybrid structures which are
                        relatively stable in the aqueous environment. Also, it was demonstrated that
                        there are significant differences in local structures between water-washed
                        and acid-washed titanate nanotubes. For acid-washed nanotube, the local
                        structure can be changed reversibly into an anatase-like structure by the
                        incorporation of HQ, MEHQ, or CAT. This provides important clues for
                        understanding the structure of titanate nanotubes and the interaction
                        between ligands and nanotube surfaces. The hybrid system of titanate
                        nanotubes/organic molecules has optical absorption significantly beyond 700
                        nm. This system could have very important applications in photocatalysis and
                        photovoltaic devices.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/kk91fk598</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:2r36tx594</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T17:43:16Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>The weight and way of shared laughter in Dyadic
                        relationships</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Kurtz, Laura Elizabeth</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Psychology and
                        Neuroscience</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Algoe, Sara</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2014</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Laughter is largely considered a social behavior and has been
                        correlated with a number of relationship-relevant outcomes. Yet the majority
                        of the existing research has employed methods that focus specifically on an
                        individual's laughter, while neglecting to address the influence of the
                        surrounding social context. We argue that when a laugh occurs within the
                        presence of another person, as it most often does, whether or not the other
                        person is also laughing (i.e., whether the laugh is shared versus solo) may
                        have tremendous consequences for the pair's relationship. The current
                        studies tested the hypothesis that shared laughter would promote
                        relationship wellbeing via increased positive emotions, decreased negative
                        emotions, and increased perceptions of similarity. A series of online and
                        laboratory studies provide correlational and causal support for these
                        hypotheses. Results are discussed in terms of their implications for future
                        research pertaining to the importance of shared laughter within social
                        contexts.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Master of Arts</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/2r36tx594</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:hd76s012n</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T17:43:35Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Discriminative Subgraph Pattern Mining and Its Applications</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Jin, Ning</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Computer
                        Science</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Wang, Wei</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2012</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>My dissertation concentrates on two problems in mining
                        discriminative subgraphs: how to efficiently identify subgraph patterns that
                        discriminate two sets of graphs and how to improve discrimination power of
                        subgraph patterns by allowing flexibility. To achieve high efficiency, I
                        adapted evolutionary computation to subgraph mining and proposed to learn
                        how to prune search space from search history. To allow flexibility, I
                        proposed to loosely assemble small rigid graphs for structural flexibility
                        and I proposed a label relaxation technique for label flexibility. I
                        evaluated how applications of discriminative subgraphs can benefit from more
                        efficient and effective mining algorithms. Experimental results showed that
                        the proposed algorithms outperform other algorithms in terms of speed. In
                        addition, using discriminative subgraph patterns found by the proposed
                        algorithms leads to competitive or higher classification accuracy than other
                        methods. Allowing structural flexibility enables users to identify subgraph
                        patterns with even higher discrimination power.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Computer</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>science</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/hd76s012n</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:08612n62k</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T17:43:46Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Mea lux, meum desiderium: Cicero's letters to Terentia and marital
                        ideals</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Peterkin, Jetta Maria</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Classics</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Riess, Werner</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>December 2010</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>The marriage of the famed Roman orator Cicero to his first wife
                        Terentia is often cited as an example of Roman marital relationships because
                        of the letters that survive from him to her. However, their marriage needs
                        to be compared to other sources that describe marital interactions to
                        determine if we can use it as a model for other Roman unions. The lack of a
                        variety of sources from Roman marriages has limited this investigation to
                        comparing Cicero and Terentia to the ideals that are present in epigraphic
                        and epistolographic records. The results demonstrate that, within certain
                        socio-economic parameters, the marriage of Cicero and Terentia would have
                        been considered normative by other Romans. As such, their relationship is an
                        effective model for how Romans would have viewed a successful
                        marriage.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/08612n62k</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:4x51hj12b</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T17:56:57Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Focal adhesion kinase in cardiac development and disease</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>DiMichele, Laura Antonietta</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Medicine, Department of Pathology and Laboratory
                        Medicine</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Taylor, Joan</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>December 2007</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>In the United States, nearly 80 million adults are affected by
                        cardiovascular disease. The spectrum of disease range from congenital
                        structural defects to acquired structural changes in response to an
                        increased hemodynamic load on the heart, myocardial infarction, or hormonal
                        imbalance. Cardiovascular disease accounts for significant amounts of
                        morbidity and mortality and is currently the number one cause of death in
                        the U.S. Congenital heart disease is the most common cause of infant death
                        from birth defects. Genetic studies in lower vertebrates have been critical
                        to the understanding of the specific factors required for heart development.
                        These studies suggest that cardiac abnormalities may be mediated by abnormal
                        regulation of transcription factors. Although several transcription factors
                        involved in cardiac development have been elucidated, much regarding
                        specific signaling pathways implicated in abnormal cardiogenesis is still
                        unknown. Acquired cardiac disease can occur in response to various stimuli.
                        For example, an increased hemodynamic load can result in compensatory
                        hypertrophic remodeling and may progress to pathologic hypertrophy. A common
                        manifestation of this pathologic process is a constellation of symptoms
                        known as congestive heart failure. Focal Adhesion Kinase (FAK) is
                        responsible for a variety of biological functions including cell adhesion,
                        migration, proliferation, and survival. Several studies demonstrated a role
                        for FAK binding partners and/or for upstream activators of FAK throughout
                        cardiac development and disease. However, since germline deletion of FAK
                        results in early embryonic lethality, it is difficult to study the specific
                        role for FAK in cardiac development and disease. Therefore, we addressed
                        this issue by creating several mouse models which express tissue specific
                        expression of FAK, or its dominant negative FAK-related non-kinase (FRNK).
                        We used these mice to investigate the role of FAK in cardiogenesis, anabolic
                        growth, and cardiac disease. Collectively, these conditional mouse models
                        demonstrated that FAK activity and/or its expression is required for
                        cardiomyocyte proliferation throughout development, is dispensable for
                        anabolic growth of the heart, and is necessary and sufficient for the
                        induction of cardiac hypertrophy. Further characterization of the precise
                        signaling pathways downstream of FAK may lead to targets for future
                        therapeutic intervention to treat congenital and acquired heart
                        disease.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/4x51hj12b</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:n009w2390</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T17:57:07Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Displaying Authority: Guns, Political Legitimacy, and Martial
                        Pageantry in Tokugawa Japan, 1600-1868</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Lauro, Daniele</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        History</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Pitelka, Morgan</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2013</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>From the end of the sixteenth century on, firearms in Japan are
                        increasingly found in contexts other than the battlefield. A perusal of the
                        Records of the Tokugawa Family (Tokugawa Jikki) - the military clan that
                        ruled Japan from 1603 to 1868 - reveals, for instance, that guns were often
                        involved in ritual practices performed by the warrior elite, such as
                        weddings, funerals, hunting parades, and celebrations of the New Year.
                        Moreover, it was common for both the shogun and the domainal lords (daimyô)
                        to display firearms and other weapons during public audiences and military
                        parades. By considering different ritual practices that involved the display
                        of military power such as daimyo processions to Edo, shogunal pilgrimages to
                        Nikko, military reviews, large-scale hunts and other pageants, this paper
                        argues that during the Tokugawa period guns were often used by the warrior
                        elite as tools to shore up authority, legitimize the political order, and
                        reinforce ideals of warrior identity.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Master of Arts</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>History</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/n009w2390</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:ww72bb54s</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:00:14Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Moral moods</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Schellenberg, Ingra</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Philosophy</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Prinz, Jesse J.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>December 2006</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>In this dissertation, I argue that moods can be intentional
                        states, that is, they can be about something. I make this case by exploring
                        the moods that underlie two psychopathological diagnoses: depression and
                        borderline personality disorder (BPD). The view that moods can be
                        intentional is counter to dominant positions in both philosophy and
                        medicine. This project has three elements. First, I critically examine
                        current medical approaches to depression and BPD. I distinguish two dominant
                        models of medical practice and argue that many medical practitioners within
                        both models (implicitly) deny the potential intentionality of moods. This
                        results in a widespread medical mischaracterisation of depression and BPD.
                        Second, I argue that the intentional features of those moods that underlie
                        depression and BPD can be appreciated when one assumes the role first of
                        'affective reconstructor' and then of 'affective interlocutor.' Affective
                        reconstructors explore the origins of someone's mood with the aim of
                        identifying its intentional object(s). If an intentional object is found,
                        one can assume the role of affective interlocutor. In that role one actively
                        engages with the mood experiencer, carefully considering whether those
                        intentional object(s) fit appropriately with the mood. Third, once the moods
                        that underlie depression and BPD are seen as potentially intentional, I
                        argue that they may be 'moral moods.' I use case studies of sufferers of
                        depression and BPD, particularly the character of Sophie (from William
                        Styron's novel Sophie's Choice) and Lilah, a composite of several patients
                        diagnosed with BPD. I argue that their moods are responses to moral
                        violation. Non-intentional accounts of moods, either philosophical or
                        medical, will fail to acknowledge the moral dimension of these moods. I
                        argue that this is a substantial failure, both for Sophie and Lilah and also
                        for those around them, who will miss the opportunity to fully understand
                        their experiences.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/ww72bb54s</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:8s45q8848</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:28:36Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>The role of RhoA signaling pathways in regulating HIV-1
                        replication</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Loomis, Rebecca Jo</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Medicine, Curriculum in Genetics and Molecular
                        Biology</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Su, Lishan</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2006</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>RhoGTPases are involved in regulating important cellular
                        processes including cytoskeletal organization, gene transcription and
                        membrane vesicle transport – poising RhoGTPases to link these pathways to
                        HIV-1 replication. However, RhoGTPase function in HIV-1 replication is
                        essentially unknown. RhoA activation can be modulated by the cytoplasmic
                        tail of the HIV-1 transmembrane envelope glycoprotein through its
                        interaction with p115RhoGEF, a RhoA specific activator. Furthermore,
                        activation of the RhoA signaling pathway inhibits HIV-1 gene expression. To
                        investigate how RhoA pathways modulate HIV-1 replication, I tested
                        individual RhoA effectors. Rho-associated kinase (ROCK) specifically
                        inhibits HIV-1 gene expression in T cells. A ROCK specific inhibitor
                        counteracts RhoA inhibition of HIV-1 gene expression, indicating that RhoA
                        signals via ROCK to inhibit HIV-1. HIV-1 LTR mutations in either the NF-κB
                        or Sp1 binding sites abrogate ROCK-mediated inhibition. ROCK may disrupt the
                        cooperative interaction between NF-κB and Sp1 or modulate epigenetic
                        regulation to inhibit HIV-1 gene expression. Additionally, I identified a
                        disparate role for the RhoA effector, citron kinase. Citron kinase
                        preferentially enhances HIV-1 virion production by promoting exocytosis.
                        This activity depends on the leucine zipper, Rho-binding and zinc-finger
                        domains, but not the kinase activity, of citron kinase. Although citron
                        kinase-mediated enhancement of HIV-1 replication is late domain independent,
                        an intact late endosomal sorting pathway is required. Citron kinase may act
                        as a scaffold, linking host proteins to the endosomal sorting and exosomal
                        pathways. I also found a functional interaction between citron kinase and
                        the ESCRT-I component, Tsg101. Ectopic expression of either citron kinase or
                        Tsg101 enhances HIV-1 virion production, however, coexpression of citron
                        kinase and Tsg101 inhibits HIV-1 replication. This functional interaction is
                        mediated by the kinase activity of citron and the PTAP-binding region of
                        Tsg101. The two activities of citron kinase involved in HIV-1 regulation are
                        distinct and independent of one another. In summary, I identified two RhoA
                        effectors, ROCK and citron kinase to regulate HIV-1 replication. ROCK
                        specifically inhibits HIV-1 gene expression while citron kinase demonstrates
                        a disparate role. These RhoA effectors may provide novel targets for
                        developing antiviral therapeutics and further our understanding of the role
                        of RhoA signaling pathways in HIV-1 replication.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/8s45q8848</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:d217qp57h</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:31:24Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Choosing Between Multinomial Logit and Multinomial Probit Models for
                        Analysis of Unordered Choice Data</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Kropko, Jonathan</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Political
                        Science</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Rabinowitz, George</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>May 2008</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Political researchers are often confronted with unordered
                        categorical variables, such as the vote-choice of a particular voter in a
                        multiparty election. In such situations, re-searchers must choose an
                        appropriate empirical model to analyze this data. The two most commonly used
                        models are the multinomial logit (MNL) model and the multinomial probit
                        (MNP) model. MNL is simpler, but also makes the often erroneous independence
                        of irrelevant alternatives (IIA) assumption. MNP is computationally
                        intensive, but does not assume IIA, and for this reason many researchers
                        have assumed that MNP is a better model. Little evidence exists, however,
                        which shows that MNP will provide more accurate results than MNL. In this
                        paper, I conduct computer simulations and show that MNL nearly always
                        provides more accurate results than MNP, even when the IIA assumption is
                        severely violated. The results suggest that researchers in the field should
                        reconsider use of MNP as the most reliable empirical model.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/d217qp57h</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:7w62f830j</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:31:35Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Arbitrage: A Critique of the Political Economy of Finance</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Hardin, Carolyn</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Communication</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Bryan, Dick</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Palm, Michael</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Sharma, Sarah</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Grossberg, Lawrence</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Pryke, Michael</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>In the wake of the 2007-09 financial crisis and growing economic
                        inequality fueled by financial activity, it cannot be left to mainstream
                        economists to define and explain finance. This dissertation reexamines
                        finance and the political, social and cultural foundations ignored by
                        economists. In the first chapter, I argue for the importance of arbitrage, a
                        trading strategy defined by buying low priced securities and selling the
                        same securities for higher prices in two different markets. Arbitrage is the
                        conceptual linchpin of modern financial economics but that discipline fails
                        to explain the source of arbitrage profit. In the second chapter, I explore
                        whether Marxist economics can offer a theorization of arbitrage profit.
                        While much of Marxist scholarship too quickly dismisses the significance of
                        finance, there is room for considering arbitrage to be a form of
                        exploitation. In line with innovative Marxist work on finance, I apply a new
                        framework for understanding value to arbitrage in the third chapter. I
                        suggest that arbitrage can be understood as an apparatus of capture in which
                        value founded on social mattering is captured in uneven relations of power.
                        In the fourth chapter, I review the history of arbitrage and suggest that
                        arbitrage is most successful when arbitrageurs can use advantageous
                        differentials in communication networks and/or price stabilizing derivatives
                        contracts to simulate instantaneous trading. A special form of arbitrage I
                        call money machine arbitrage takes place when structural inequalities of
                        price allow for continuous profit making. In the fifth chapter, I offer a
                        final concept necessary for understanding arbitrage as an apparatus of
                        capture: the axiomatic. The axiomatic is the complex system of regulative
                        statements and social relations that enable capture. In the final
                        substantive chapter, I detail the arbitrage in subprime mortgage backed
                        securities in the run up to the 2007-09 financial crisis and sketch some
                        aspects of the axiomatic that can be gleaned from that story. I conclude
                        that the taken-for-granted notion of “risk,” as a necessary way of making
                        wealth and the correlate of return in financial economics, is central to the
                        axiomatic of finance and thus financial profit making.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Communication</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Arbitrage</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Political Economy</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Critical Theory</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Finance</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Technology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Cultural Studies</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/7w62f830j</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:cj82k736b</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:31:45Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Iridium-catalyzed reduction of C-X bonds (X = F, Cl, Br, I, O) bonds
                        with triethylsilane</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Yang, Jian</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Chemistry</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Brookhart, Maurice</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>August 2008</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Alkyl halides are generally reduced with trialkyl tin hydrides
                        via a radical chain mechanism. Alternative reduction procedures are desired
                        owing to the toxicity of the tin reagents and problems separating tin
                        byproducts from reduction products. We have discovered and developed a
                        highly efficient and environmental friendly procedure for the reduction of a
                        broad range of alkyl halides by triethylsilane reagents with cationic
                        iridium pincer catalysts. In-depth mechanistic studies have been carried out
                        which have revealed a unique catalytic cycle. The electrophilic iridium
                        hydride complex binds and activates the silane. This complex transfers
                        "Et3Si+" to the halide forming a highly active bridged halonium ion which is
                        rapidly reduced by the iridium dihydride remaining following silyl transfer
                        and the cationic iridium hydride complex is thus regenerated. All key
                        intermediates have been identified by in situ NMR monitoring and kinetic
                        studies have been completed. The key Ir(silane)intermediate has even been
                        isolated and fully characterized by NMR spectroscopy and X-ray
                        crystallography, which shows an unprecedented example of a cationic
                        transition metal eta1-silane complex. In application of this novel chemistry
                        to other organic functional groups, we have been particularly drawn to the
                        cleavage and reduction of alkyl ethers, due to its several potential
                        applications. We have found that these cationic iridium pincer catalysts are
                        highly active for the room-temperature cleavage and reduction of a wide
                        variety of unactivated alkyl ethers with triethylsilane. For example,
                        diethyl ether can be readily converted to two equivalents of ethane and
                        Et3SiOSiEt3. Poly(ethylene glycol) can be readily degraded to
                        Et3SiOCH2CH2OSiEt3 and ethane. Mechanistic studies have revealed the full
                        details of the catalytic cycle with the resting state(s) depending on the
                        basicity of the alkyl ether. The key intermediate
                        diethyl(triethylsilyl)oxonium ion has been isolated and fully characterized
                        by low temperature NMR spectroscopies and X-ray
                        crystallography.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/cj82k736b</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:tx31qh74n</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:32:49Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Interplay between metformin and serotonin transport in the
                        gastrointestinal tract: a novel mechanism for the intestinal absorption and
                        adverse effects of metformin</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Han, Tianxiang</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>Eshelman School of Pharmacy</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Thakker, Dhiren</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2013</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Metformin is a widely prescribed drug for Type II diabetes
                        mellitus. Previous studies have shown that this highly hydrophilic and
                        charged compound traverses predominantly paracellularly across the Caco-2
                        cell monolayer, a well-established model for human intestinal epithelium.
                        However, oral bioavailability of metformin is significantly higher than that
                        of the paracellular probe, mannitol (~60% vs ~16%). Based on these
                        observations, the Thakker laboratory proposed a sponge hypothesis (Proctor
                        et al., 2008) which states that the functional synergy between apical (AP)
                        transporters and paracellular transport enhances the intestinal absorption
                        of metformin. This dissertation work aims to identify AP uptake transporters
                        of metformin, determine their polarized localization, and elucidate their
                        roles in the intestinal absorption and adverse effects of metformin.
                        Chemical inhibition and transporter-knockdown studies revealed that four
                        transporters, namely, organic cation transporter 1 (OCT1), plasma membrane
                        monoamine transporter (PMAT), serotonin reuptake transporter (SERT) and
                        choline high-affinity transporter (CHT) contribute to AP uptake of metformin
                        in Caco-2 cells. Although AP intestinal localization of PMAT, SERT and CHT
                        has been established, the intestinal membrane localization of OCT1 is
                        ambiguous in the literature. In this dissertation work, functional and
                        immunostaining studies showed that OCT1 is localized in the AP membrane of
                        Caco-2 cells and human and mouse intestinal epithelia. Since this
                        dissertation data showed for the first time that metformin is a substrate of
                        SERT, the in vivo role of this transporter in mediating metformin oral
                        absorption was investigated. The SERT-selective chemical inhibitor,
                        paroxetine, decreased metformin systemic AUC0-6h by 9% (p&lt;0.05), and in
                        mSert-/- mice, metformin systemic AUC0-6h was lowered by 6% (p&lt;0.05).
                        Because SERT mediates the reuptake of serotonin which modulates
                        gastrointestinal (GI) functions, its role in metformin-mediated GI adverse
                        effects, such as diarrhea, was investigated in a mouse model. Results showed
                        that metformin induced a 4-fold increase (p&lt;0.001) in intestinal
                        motility, and a 50% increase (p&lt;0.05) in water content of the large
                        intestine. These effects were diminished by serotonin receptor 4 antagonist
                        GR113808, suggesting that metformin could cause GI adverse effects, such as
                        diarrhea, by inhibiting SERT-mediated serotonin re-uptake and subsequent
                        serotonin-induced increased GI motility and
                        water-retention.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>sciences</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Pharmaceutical</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/tx31qh74n</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:np193931r</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:33:06Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>POINT-OF-CARE HIV TESTING FOR EARLY INFANT DIAGNOSIS DURING THE
                        POSTPARTUM PERIOD: TIMING AND TYPE OF TEST MATTERS</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Smith, Emily</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>Gillings School of Global Public Health, Department of
                        Epidemiology</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Hudgens, Michael</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Stringer, Jeffrey</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Van Rie, Annelies</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Wheeler, Stephanie</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Miller, William</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>December 2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>In the past decade, large gains have been made in reducing
                        pediatric HIV infections during the prenatal or peripartum period. However,
                        recent changes in the World Health Organization (WHO) breastfeeding
                        guidelines will likely shift the majority of new infant HIV infections to
                        the postnatal period1,2. Although breastfeeding guidelines have changed,
                        early infant diagnosis (EID) recommendations have not been updated. In this
                        dissertation, I evaluated the performance of two HIV rapid tests, Determine
                        and Unigold, on a cohort of 121 Malawian HIV-exposed, breast-fed infants who
                        were HIV negative at 6 weeks postpartum from 3 to 18 months of age. I also
                        evaluated the cost-effectiveness for several EID strategies that varied in
                        type, timing, and number of rapid tests, including an Alere test, a
                        point-of-care virological assay, through Markov modeling. Among 121
                        HIV-exposed infants, the estimated specificity increased quicker for Unigold
                        to 100% (95% CI: 95.4, 100.0) by age 12 months compared with 95.6% (90.7,
                        100.0) by 15 months of age for Determine. Both tests failed to detect
                        several incident HIV infections. Seroreversion occurred sooner with Unigold
                        with an earlier mean time to seroreversion by 62 days (95% CI: 60, 64).
                        Among 21 different EID strategies, the lowest costing strategy was testing
                        once with Unigold at 9 months ($18.20 per infant) and testing twice with
                        Alere at 6 and 15 months ($145.60 per infant). The strategies with the
                        lowest and highest effectiveness were testing once with Unigold at 9 months
                        (337,806 disability-adjusted-life years [DALYs]) and testing twice at 6 and
                        15 months with Alere (192,588 DALYs). After sequentially comparing all
                        strategies in ranked order by costs, six remained cost-effective. Our
                        findings highlight that the type and timing of rapid test matters greatly in
                        regard to accurately identifying and ruling out pediatric HIV infections.
                        Updated guidelines for use of rapid tests in young HIV-exposed children that
                        explicitly takes the type of test and infant age into account are urgently
                        needed to ensure optimal care for the 1.5 million HIV-exposed infants born
                        annually, especially in light of the new breastfeeding
                        guidelines.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Epidemiology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>HIV/AIDS</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Policy</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>PMTCT</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Early infant diagnosis</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>HIV rapid tests</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/np193931r</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:1j92g752z</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:33:44Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Military Service, Deployments, And Exposures in Relation to
                        Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Etiology and Survival</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Beard, John</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>Gillings School of Global Public Health, Department of
                        Epidemiology</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Gammon, Marilie D.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Baird, Coleen</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Kamel, Freya</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Richardson, David</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Engel, Lawrence</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a debilitating
                        neurodegenerative disease. Its importance as a public health problem lies in
                        its generally rapid progression and often fatal outcome. ALS rates have been
                        reported to be higher among U.S. military veterans, of which there are
                        currently more than 21 million, but the causal agents related to military
                        service have not been identified. Previous studies were limited by reliance
                        on mortality as a surrogate for incidence, a dearth of survival analyses,
                        lack of clinical data, low statistical power, and limited exposure
                        assessment. We used information from Genes and Environmental Exposures in
                        Veterans with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, a study of 630 veteran ALS
                        cases and 975 frequency-matched veteran controls to 1) evaluate associations
                        between aspects of military service, deployments, and 40 exposures and ALS
                        etiology; and 2) evaluate associations between aspects of military service,
                        deployments, and 40 exposures and ALS survival. We used inverse probability
                        weighting to evaluate and adjust for potential selection bias resulting from
                        studying cases who likely represent long survivors and controls who may be
                        different from U.S. military veterans at large. We observed several inverse
                        associations between ALS and military service and deployment variables, but
                        these may be because the control group was comprised of many career military
                        veterans. We found lower odds of ALS among officers and higher odds among
                        veterans whose longest deployment was World War II or the Korean War. There
                        was no difference in the odds of ALS among veterans of the Air Force, Army,
                        Marines, and Navy. ALS was more common among veterans who had direct contact
                        with eight exposures incurred during deployment to four major wars. We did
                        not find strong evidence that military-related factors were associated with
                        shorter ALS survival. While we cannot exclude the effects of uncontrolled
                        selection bias or confounding by non-military exposures on our results, they
                        provide clues to potential causal factors underlying the apparent increase
                        of ALS among military veterans and, therefore, require replication and
                        further study. Furthermore, the null association we found between
                        military-related factors and ALS survival may be comforting to ALS cases who
                        are military veterans.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Industrial safety</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Armed Forces</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Epidemiology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Military Service</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Case-control</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Environmental Exposures</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Inverse Probability Weighting</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Survival</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/1j92g752z</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:7s75dc47g</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:33:52Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>The Effect of a CPET Familiarization Session on Aerobic Capacity
                        (VO2MAX) in Sedentary Middle-Aged Females</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Brooks, Christopher</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Exercise and Sport
                        Science</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Hanson, Erik</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Ryan, Eric</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Battaglini, Claudio L.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Wagoner, Chad</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2017</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Cardiorespiratory capacity (VO2Max) is assessed by performing a
                        cardiorespiratory exercise test (CPET). Research postulates that a learning
                        effect can compromise the accuracy of the CPET. Healthy populations produce
                        high CPET reproducibility, whereas clinical populations are inconclusive.
                        The purpose of this study was to examine the effect of a familiarization
                        session on aerobic capacity in sedentary middle-aged females. This study
                        recruited 6 female participants ages 35-65. Test protocol consisted of a
                        familiarization session, a VO2Max pre-test, and a VO2Max post-test. VO2Max,
                        respiratory exchange ratio (RER), and maximal heart rate (HRMax) were
                        analyzed using a paired samples t-tests. Relative and absolute VO2Max
                        significantly decreased by -9.68% (p=0.03) and -9.33% (p=0.03), from pre to
                        post. No significant differences were observed for RER and HRMax (p=0.23;
                        p=0.30). This potentially indicates the familiarization effectively
                        mitigated a learning effect; however, due to the small sample size a larger
                        sample is necessary to re-evaluate these preliminary
                        findings.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Master of Arts</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>maximal exercise</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>VO2</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>cancer</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/7s75dc47g</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:2b88qc270</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:34:12Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Hume's treatise and the theory of ideas</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Kelahan, Emily M.</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Philosophy</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Nelson, Alan Jean</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2011</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Hume's Treatise of Human Nature has long been evaluated in terms
                        of the skepticism-naturalism interpretive dichotomy. According to this
                        interpretation, there are two distinct and often diametrically opposed
                        Humes: a skeptic concerned to eradicate dubious metaphysical views and a
                        naturalist concerned to develop a science of human nature. The skeptical
                        Hume applies the theory of ideas developed in Book I of the Treatise to the
                        phenomena he seeks to explain and nearly obliterates them. That leaves the
                        science of human nature weak and without phenomena to explain in Books II
                        and III. The naturalistic Hume, in contrast, is able to develop a robust
                        science of human nature in Books II and III of the Treatise, but does so at
                        the expense of completely abandoning the theory of ideas developed in Book
                        I. In short, the familiar skepticism-naturalism interpretive dichotomy has
                        it that Hume either successfully developed a science of human nature without
                        the theory of ideas or else stubbornly held on to his theory of ideas at the
                        cost of a robust science of human nature. This is a false dichotomy. There
                        is one Hume, not two, who both adheres to the theory of ideas throughout the
                        Treatise and develops a robust science of human nature. Hume accomplished
                        much with little in his Treatise. Most importantly, he demolished
                        extravagant metaphysical theories of various types and developed a robust
                        science of human nature. Both feats were accomplished via his oft
                        criticized, but little understood theory of ideas. Contrary to the
                        prevailing opinion, the theory of ideas stands not in opposition to Hume's
                        naturalistic project of developing a science of human nature, but rather is
                        the foundation of that very project. I develop and defend an interpretation
                        of Hume's theory of ideas according to which it succeeds in eradicating
                        dubious metaphysical views, but also supports, rather than undermines his
                        science of human nature.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/2b88qc270</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:p5547r44x</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:34:38Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Structural dynamics of retroviral genomes</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Grohman, Jacob K.</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Medicine, Department of Biochemistry and
                        Biophysics</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Weeks, Kevin</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>May 2012</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Retroviral RNA genomes form myriad structures that are governed
                        by critical interactions with either the nucleocapsid (NC) protein or the
                        nucleocapsid domain of Gag polyprotein. I have pioneered two powerful
                        technologies, based on SHAPE (selective 2'-hydroxyl acylation analyzed by
                        primer extension), to explore interactions between NC and the RNA genomes of
                        the xenotropic murine leukemia virus related virus (XMRV) and the Moloney
                        murine leukemia virus (MuLV). In the first approach, ultra-sensitive SHAPE,
                        I developed a two-color capillary electrophoresis instrument with low
                        attomole (10-18) sensitivity. New analysis approaches and the high
                        sensitivity of this instrument allowed me to obtain unprecedented
                        single-nucleotide resolution structures from authentic RNA genomes of MuLV
                        and XMRV. In the second approach, time-resolved SHAPE, I used a fast acting
                        SHAPE reagent to reveal the structural biogenesis of NC binding to the MuLV
                        retroviral RNA genome. The data generated using these SHAPE-based
                        technologies allow me to propose detailed mechanisms for both the specific
                        RNA binding and the chaperone activities of NC.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/p5547r44x</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:n296wz234</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:34:53Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Accent Placement in Japanese Blends</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Broad, Rachel</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Linguistics</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Moreton, Elliott</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Pertsova, Katya</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Smith, Jennifer L.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>This thesis investigates the factors influencing accent
                        placement in Japanese lexical blends (e.g. gozira ‘Godzilla,’ gorira
                        ‘gorilla’ + kuzira ‘whale’). Previous studies on English blends have claimed
                        that the relative contributions of source words are influenced by factors
                        such as their linear order (Bat-El &amp; Cohen 2012, Gries 2004a,b) or the
                        privileged position of the head (Shaw 2013). I present accent data collected
                        for a corpus of Japanese blends to show that their accent placement is
                        determined by head faithfulness rather than linear order or patterns found
                        in other word formation processes. This work has several implications.
                        First, it provides support for the claim that the position of the head is
                        relevant in blend formation. It also demonstrates that factors influencing
                        blends are cross-linguistically relevant. Finally, it provides evidence that
                        blending is a distinct process and that the internal morphological structure
                        of blends is unlike that of compounds and reduced
                        compounds.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Master of Arts</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Linguistics</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Japanese</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Blends</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Accent</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/n296wz234</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:9s161628x</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:35:02Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Framing analysis of newspapers coverage of Max Mosley’s Nazi
                        orgy</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Aljoura, Loubna</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Media and Journalism</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Boynton, Lois A.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>August 2009</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>On March 28, 2008, The News of the World, a British tabloid
                        newspaper, published a front page story accompanied by a video saying that
                        Max Mosley, the president of the Federation Internationale de l'Automobile
                        was involved in a depraved Nazi sadomasochistic orgy in a private flat in
                        Chelsea. Explored in this thesis are the story frames and image restoration
                        strategies and postures used by Mosley. Questions of how the news media
                        covered the Mosley story as well as the image restoration strategies and
                        postures evident in Mosley's response are explored using the qualitative
                        content analysis of the news coverage of two British newspapers. This study
                        is significant in that it explored a crisis that occurred by a leader of a
                        private organization whose sexual behaviors were conducted in a private
                        place, and, ultimately, the courts sided with him in protecting his
                        privacy.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/9s161628x</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:bn9996777</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:35:25Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>On the Line: The Working Lives of Latinos and African Americans in the
                        New South</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Ribas, Vanesa</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Sociology</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Hagan, Jacqueline</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2012</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>This dissertation is an ethnography of a meatpacking plant in
                        North Carolina, where I held a job as a production worker for sixteen months
                        totaling more than 3,500 hours of participant observation between August
                        2009 and December 2010. I also spent countless hours socializing outside the
                        factory with worker-friends I came to know very well over two years, and
                        conducted twenty-five in-depth interviews with Latina/o and African American
                        workers. In this project, I examine how Latina/o migrants are becoming
                        incorporated in the New South. In particular, I draw attention to how groups
                        develop a sense of their group position in a complex map of hierarchical
                        relations through boundary processes that are structured in key domains, in
                        this case, the workplace. In addition to preconditioning factors such as
                        ethnoracial panoramas in origin countries, the racial/ethnic composition of
                        labor and the authority structure, variation in labor discipline regimes,
                        and social perceptions about the nature of particular kinds of work and the
                        qualities of particular types of workers are all important dimensions that
                        account for how Latinos carve out their place in the New American South. In
                        marked contrast to the fears of some scholars and pundits, and against the
                        conclusions put forth in recent research on the topic of intergroup
                        relations in the U.S. South, African American workers do not talk or behave
                        as if they are especially threatened by economic, political, or cultural
                        competition from Latinos/migrants, and this finding holds regardless of
                        whether African Americans are the majority or minority in a specific
                        department. On the other hand, Latina/os deploy an elaborate array of
                        racialized action that is substantially inflected negatively towards African
                        Americans, that reflects and reinforces ethnoracial boundaries between
                        Latinos and African Americans, represents definitively Latinos'
                        determination to achieve incorporation as nonblacks, and may bolster the
                        hegemony of whiteness in the emerging order.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Sociology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/bn9996777</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:d791sg30j</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:35:31Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>PARENT INTERACTIVE BEHAVIORS AND LANGUAGE DEVELOPMENT IN CHILDREN WITH
                        AUTISM SPECTRUM DISORDER, FRAGILE X SYNDROME, AND NO DISABILITY</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Durante, Genna Rose</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Education</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Simeonsson, Rune</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2013</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Language and communication deficits are key features of both
                        autism spectrum disorder (ASD) and fragile X syndrome (FXS). Previous
                        literature has identified parent interaction behaviors as a potential
                        predictive factor in language development for children with and without
                        disabilities, but the relationship between variables is largely unknown for
                        school-age children. In this study, the relationship between parent
                        interactive behavior and language gains was assessed for 66 school-age boys
                        with ASD, FXS and ASD, FXS only, and no disability. Parents interacted with
                        their child in a free play activity and parent behaviors were rated from
                        videotape on the domains of warmth, sensitivity, responsiveness,
                        encouragement of initiative, stimulation value and elaborativeness. Results
                        indicated that parental warmth was a significant predictor of later language
                        gains, while the other domains were not. These results support the linkage
                        of parent interactive behaviors to developmental outcomes during the
                        school-age years.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Master of Arts</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Education</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/d791sg30j</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:r494vk23n</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:35:41Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Egyptian Darkness: Antebellum Reconstruction and Southern Illinois in
                        the Republican Imagination, 1854-1861</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Burke, Eric</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        History</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Barney, William</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Watson, Harry L.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Glatthaar, Joseph</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2016</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Historians have identified an antebellum Republican “critique of
                        the South” outlining the detrimental effects of slavery on white Southern
                        society and the vital importance of “reconstructing” the white South in the
                        image of the free labor agrarian North following the eventual collapse of
                        slavery. The efforts to follow through with this transformation have
                        historiographically been relegated to the efforts of radical Republicans to
                        reconstruct the ex-Confederacy between 1863 and 1877. This paper argues that
                        Republican strategies and efforts to “reconstruct” the white South were
                        evident during the late antebellum period (1848-1861) applied to the
                        southern counties of Illinois, inhabited chiefly by Southern "poor white”
                        migrants. These efforts to dispel the “Egyptian darkness” of southern
                        Illinois can be seen as an early laboratory of Republican reconstruction
                        strategies.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Master of Arts</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Reconstruction</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>American</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Republican</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Antebellum</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Civil War</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>history</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Illinois</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>History</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/r494vk23n</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:9p290946m</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:35:51Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Essays in microfinance- and social network-driven marketing at the
                        base of the pyramid</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Ong, L. Lin</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>Kenan-Flagler Business School</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Kushwaha, Tarun</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Dinner, Isaac</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Jones Christensen, Lisa</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Gielens, Katrijn</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Balasubramanian, Sridhar</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2016</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>In the past thirty years, microfinance has innovated the
                        provision of financial services to microenterprises (businesses with five or
                        fewer employees), growing aggressively to a USD $50 billion industry. A
                        marketing lens gives us the empirical and theoretical foundations to
                        understand this field, providing the tools to synthesize the ideas of social
                        capital, microfinance, and networks into managerially important insights. I
                        explore these concepts using a novel dataset assembled from surveys,
                        personal networks, interviews, administrative banking data, and a randomized
                        control trial (RCT) of microentrepreneurs in Kenya, where microenterprises
                        are estimated to represent over 20% of the country’s total employment. Essay
                        one builds on the relationship marketing literature’s identification of
                        commitment as critical to maintaining successful business-to-consumer
                        relationships. I find a positive relationship between household consumption
                        and client commitment – however, this includes not only commitment to the
                        firm, but also to their loan peers. This has implications for MFI client
                        strategy, motivation to cultivate both positive client commitment towards
                        the firm as well as social capital within the client’s intra-firm network.
                        The second essay tackles an endogenous question: which came first, social
                        capital or financial success? Although social capital is commonly accepted
                        in economic development theory as a key driver of financial success, the
                        methodological difficulty of studying its causal impact leave a gap in the
                        literature. I use a RCT to administer a financial training, providing a
                        channel to improve financial success. While we find that the training does
                        significantly impact financial literacy and MFI financial measures, we do
                        not find any moderating impact of baseline social capital on financial
                        outcomes. This study provides a counterargument to the conventional wisdom
                        that social capital increases efficiency of entrepreneurial information
                        acquisition and application. These dissertation results provide an
                        alternative view about the importance of social capital at the BoP: although
                        social capital is a part of financial success, it doesn’t appear to have the
                        causal impact previously theorized. Through an innovative dataset and
                        rigorous experimental methods, this dissertation provides one of the first
                        quantitative, network-based studies of social capital at the BoP.
                        Implications for managers, policy makers, and researchers are
                        discussed.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>marketing</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Entrepreneurship</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>microfinance</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>microentrepreneurship</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>social network analysis</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Marketing</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>social capital</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/9p290946m</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:v118rd62d</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:36:06Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>MICROBIAL DIVERSITY AND EVOLUTION IN GULF OF MEXICO HYPERSALINE
                        ENVIRONMENTS</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Nigro, Lisa</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Marine
                        Sciences</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>White, Brian</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>MacGregor, Barbara</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Arnosti, Carol</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Joye, Samantha</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Teske, Andreas</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>My thesis investigated the microbial diversity and taxonomic
                        composition of hypersaline and non-extreme sediment environments in the Gulf
                        of Mexico, to explore environmental controls on microbial community
                        structure and function. Environmental conditions and resource availability
                        are considered key drivers of microbial diversity and evolution. Extreme
                        environments are traditionally thought to select for more specialized
                        individuals and lower overall diversity, while non-extreme environments
                        foster diverse communities of generalists that are capable of occupying a
                        wider niche. However, extreme environments can also be heterogeneous and
                        complex systems, with a wide variety of energetic resources, providing both
                        challenges and opportunities for diversification. The sediment microbiomes
                        of this study represented natural hydrocarbon seeps, a deep-sea hypersaline
                        anoxic basin (Orca Basin, 26% salinity), Deepwater Horizon (DWH) oil
                        spill-impacted sediments, and Continental Slope background sediments, all
                        collected in November 2010. These samples were analyzed with ~5 million 16S
                        rRNA gene amplicon sequences. Shannon diversity estimates indicated that
                        Orca Basin hypersaline sediments, Continental Slope sediments, and
                        DWH-contaminated surface sediments had similar species diversity, while
                        hydrocarbon seep sediment diversity was significantly lower. UNIFRAC beta
                        diversity analysis indicated that microbial communities inhabiting Orca
                        Basin hypersaline sediments and hydrocarbon seep sediments had taxa unique
                        to each of these site types, while sediments from the Continental Slope and
                        DWH area were not statistically more similar to each other than other
                        sediments. Taxonomic analysis showed that seep cores contained higher
                        abundances of ANME-1 and Candidate Division JS1, while Orca Basin
                        hypersaline sediment-associated sequences were dominated by Marine Group I
                        Archaea, Bacteroidetes and halotolerant Deltaproteobacteria. The microbial
                        composition of the Orca Basin brine was also investigated with 16S rRNA
                        Sanger sequencing, which indicated that Candidate Division KB1-related
                        sequences were the most abundant. A partial KB1 genome sequenced from a
                        single sorted cell revealed that its proteome is dominated by acidic amino
                        acids; therefore, KB1 likely incorporates potassium ions for osmoregulation.
                        KB1 also contains complete enzymes for the acetyl-CoA pathway, and has genes
                        consistent with a glycine betaine transporter cassette as well as genes that
                        may allow for use of glycine betaine as an energy source.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Ecology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Microbiology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Sediment</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>16S rRNA</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Hypersaline</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Gulf of Mexico</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Microbial Ecology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/v118rd62d</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:37720c812</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:36:30Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Novel fluoroelastomers composed of tetrafluoroethylene and vinylidene
                        fluoride oligomers synthesized in carbon dioxide for use in soft lithography
                        to enable a platform for the fabrication of shape- and size-specific,
                        monodisperse biomaterials</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Kelly, Jennifer Yvonne</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Chemistry</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>DeSimone, Joseph M.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2008</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Fluorinated elastomers are materials with tremendous utility
                        that have found use as minimally adhesive mold materials in soft
                        lithography. The first objective of this research involved the synthesis of
                        novel functional, fluorinated oligomers in supercritical carbon dioxide
                        (scCO2) and the fabrication of the resulting fluorooligomers into solid
                        elastomers using free radical crosslinking chemistry. Commercially available
                        fluoroelastomers are typically synthesized in aqueous media using
                        fluorinated surfactants or in non-aqueous conditions using fluorinated
                        solvents. This research effort focused on the synthesis of low molecular
                        weight oligomers consisting of tetrafluoroethylene (TFE) and vinylidene
                        fluoride (VF2) with a cure site comonomer in scCO2 at low temperatures.
                        Using CO2 as a polymerization medium allows for safe handling of TFE, is
                        environmentally responsible by mitigating the typical generation of
                        halogenated, organic, or aqueous waste, and circumvents the use of
                        fluorinated surfactants as these copolymers are soluble in CO2.
                        Investigations included characterizing the fluorinated oligomers and the
                        solid elastomeric materials using NMR, DSC, TGA, GPC, IR, and via surface
                        and mechanical property analysis. The second objective of this research
                        included the use of fluoroelastomers as minimally adhesive mold materials in
                        soft lithography applications using the Particle Replication In Non-wetting
                        Templates (PRINT) technology for the fabrication of protein particles of
                        discrete size and shape. Lyophilized protein particles are generally highly
                        disperse in particle size, tend toward aggregation, and are often made
                        through complicated processes. In attempts to engineer mono-disperse protein
                        particles, the use of wet-milling, spray-freeze-drying, micro-emulsion, or
                        super critical fluid methods have been reported. The PRINT process enables a
                        gentle, facile route to mono-disperse particles composed of protein with and
                        without cargo. This research objective included fabricating protein PRINT
                        particles of varying sizes, shapes, and compositions (e.g., Abraxane,
                        albumin, tranferrin, insulin, interferon-beta, hemoglobin, trypsin,
                        horseradish peroxidase, and IgG). Several biophysical characterizations were
                        performed to verify the protein structure was not significantly altered
                        during the PRINT process, including SEM, FTIR, fluorescence microscopy, and
                        CD. Furthermore, ELISA and enzymatic activity assays were performed to
                        investigate biological integrity and function of all proteins. The PRINT
                        technology was found to be a gentle method to create nanoparticles of
                        biologically relevant proteins.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/37720c812</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:m326m1782</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:36:51Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Where disappointment and regret collide: agency, emotion, and
                        hindsight bias</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Jonsson, Eulena M.</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Psychology and
                        Neuroscience</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Sanna, Lawrence J.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>December 2007</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Emotions serve as sources of information to the decision-maker
                        and thus can impact the judgment and decision-making biases people are prone
                        to exhibit. This dissertation examines the role of specific emotions such as
                        disappointment, relief, regret, and satisfaction in the generation of
                        hindsight bias or the knew-it-all-along effect after self-relevant outcomes.
                        I proposed that such emotions provide agency or attribution information to
                        the decision-maker. Specifically, I hypothesized that when people do not
                        feel responsible for the outcome received, or circumstances-agency, they
                        experience disappointment and relief. Hindsight bias would be shown after
                        disappointment but not after relief. When people do feel responsible for the
                        outcome received, or self-agency, they experience regret and satisfaction.
                        In this case hindsight bias would not be shown after regret, but would be
                        shown after satisfaction. Study 1 (n equals 116) found support for the
                        hypotheses made in the self-agency condition, but not in the
                        circumstances-agency condition. Study 2 (n equals 260) demonstrated that it
                        is difficult to change the emotions that participants feel, with some
                        changes evidenced in direct emotion measures. In regards to hypotheses about
                        hindsight bias effects, the findings of Study 2 largely replicated those of
                        Study 1.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/m326m1782</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:4t64gn24w</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:36:52Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Essays on statistical discrimination in a dynamic framework</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Glawtschew, Rebecca M.</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Economics</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Norman, Peter</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2012</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>This dissertation consists of two papers in the field of
                        statistical discrimination. In the first paper, I determine the potential
                        causes of persistent labor market inequality by developing a dynamic model
                        of statistical discrimination in a competitive environment. In this dynamic
                        model, the forward-looking behavior of economic agents determines the
                        dynamic paths to the steady states. By characterizing these dynamic paths, I
                        am able to establish the initial conditions that can lead to each steady
                        state and to determine if it is possible to move from one steady state to
                        another. I find that the model can be broken down into two classes of
                        parameterizations. In the first class, history alone determines the final
                        outcome. In the second class, the expectations of forward-looking may agents
                        determine the final outcome. In both of these cases, moving from one steady
                        state to another is not possible. Using a simplified version of the dynamic
                        model, I also examine how the parameter values impact both the existence of
                        multiple steady states and the importance of expectations in determining the
                        final outcome. In the second paper, I consider the effectiveness of three
                        government policies designed to eliminate persistent statistical
                        discrimination in the framework of the dynamic model developed in the first
                        paper. I determine the paths that workers will take after a policy is
                        instated as well as how long a policy needs to be in place to guarantee the
                        successful elimination of discrimination. The policies I consider are (1) a
                        hiring subsidy that promotes the hiring of disadvantaged workers to the
                        better job, (2) an investment voucher that defrays the monetary cost of
                        human capital investment, and (3) an equal treatment policy under which
                        firms are required to treat workers equally across groups. I find that all
                        three policies have the potential to eliminate persistent discrimination if
                        certain conditions are met.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/4t64gn24w</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:pn89d662c</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:37:29Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Determining the Role of Prostanoids in the Pathogenesis of Pulmonary
                        Fibrosis</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Lovgren, Alysia Kern</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Medicine, Curriculum in Genetics and Molecular
                        Biology</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Koller, Beverly H.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>December 2007</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis is a relentless, fatal disease
                        characterized by alveolar epithelial cell injury, proliferation of
                        mesenchymal cell populations, and extracellular matrix deposition. Unknown
                        microinjuries to the lung initiate an aberrant repair process in susceptible
                        individuals which ultimately alters lung architecture and leads to
                        progressive loss of pulmonary function. Lipid mediators called prostanoids
                        have been implicated in both inflammatory and fibrotic signaling pathways.
                        It has been postulated that the COX-2 metabolite prostaglandin E2 (PGE2) is
                        responsible for protection against pulmonary fibrosis. To study this lipid
                        mediator, we first generated a mouse line deficient in the putative
                        cytosolic PGE2 synthase, cPGES/p23. These mice died at birth due to
                        respiratory failure, and our data shows that cPGES/p23 is a co-chaperone
                        that is important for both DNA-bindingdependent and -independent mechanisms
                        of the glucocorticoid receptor. However, characterization of primary
                        embryonic fibroblasts derived from the cPGES/p23-deficient mice, as well as
                        embryonic tissues, demonstrated that cPGES/p23 is not required for the
                        direct production of PGE2 from COX-derived PGH2. We, therefore, went on to
                        demonstrate that upregulation of PGE2 after bleomycin administration was
                        dependent on the microsomal PGE2 synthase, mPGES1. However, neither loss of
                        PGE2 synthesis nor signaling through the Gs-coupled EP2 and EP4 receptors
                        had an effect on the development of fibrotic lung disease. Interestingly, we
                        show that COX-2-dependent production of prostacyclin plays an important role
                        in the development of disease, limiting both the development of fibrosis and
                        the consequential alterations in lung mechanics. Our studies reveal an
                        important role for the COX-2-prostacyclin synthetic pathway in protection
                        from bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/pn89d662c</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:t435gd132</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:38:00Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>A Housing Submarket Approach to Neighborhood Revitalization Planning:
                        Theoretical Considerations and Empirical Justifications</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Bates, Lisa K.</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of City and Regional
                        Planning</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Quercia, Roberto</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>May 2006</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Many urban revitalization programs focus policy resources on
                        spatially defined target neighborhoods. The impacts of these programs can
                        include direct effects in the neighborhood chosen for intervention and
                        spillover effects in other neighborhoods. These unintended and sometimes
                        unpredicted effects may be positive or negative. This dissertation argues
                        that without analyzing the urban spatial structure as a set of inter-related
                        housing submarkets, planners will not be able to adequately predict and
                        evaluate the effects of revitalization policy. In doing so, the research
                        investigates the theorized nature of neighborhoods, discussing this
                        socio-cultural geography in light of the theorized nature of the housing
                        market in space. The empirical investigation, a case study of Philadelphia,
                        defines spatial housing submarkets as distinct market segments based on
                        housing quality. These submarkets are compared with first the housing market
                        implied by the theories of Alonso-Mills-Muth and Tiebout, and second with
                        the defined policy neighborhoods. The city and metropolitan area of
                        Philadelphia are found to be highly heterogeneous in housing types, with no
                        uniform pattern predicted by theory. Additionally, policy target
                        neighborhoods are often comprised of different submarkets, leading to
                        confusion in policy targeting. This research suggests that urban planners
                        should consider the geography of housing submarkets in developing
                        revitalization policies in order to choose appropriate geographic targets
                        and to predict the spatial extent of market responses.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/t435gd132</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:2j62s492k</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:38:11Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>The Effect of Knowledge of Concussion and Aggression on Head Impact
                        Biomechanics in Youth Male and Female Ice Hockey Players</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Pierce, Alice Frances</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Exercise and Sport
                        Science</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Guskiewicz, Kevin M.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2013</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>The purpose of this study was to evaluate the influence of safe
                        play knowledge and level of aggression on head impact biomechanics across
                        ice hockey players. Forty-one youth ice hockey players, 29 males and 12
                        females, participated in this study. The Safe Play Questionnaire (SPQ) and
                        the Competitive Aggressiveness and Anger Scale (CAAS) were administered at
                        the mid-point of the season. Aggressive penalty minutes were recorded
                        throughout the season. Helmets were equipped with accelerometer systems to
                        measure head impact biomechanics during practices and games. Impacts were
                        compared to grouped results of the SPQ, CAAS, and aggressive penalty minutes
                        across sexes. Less aggressive players sustained significantly less severe
                        rotational head impacts in practice compared to games and compared to
                        players with high aggression. Female and male hockey players do not differ
                        in levels of knowledge of safe play or aggression. Players with low
                        aggression sustain less severe head impacts during
                        practice.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Master of Arts</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/2j62s492k</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:rr171x313</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:38:33Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Active Prokaryotic Communities Along a Thermally and Geochemically
                        Variable Transect in Guaymas Basin Hydrothermal Sediments</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Cardman, Zena</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Marine
                        Sciences</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Teske, Andreas</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Arnosti, Carol</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>MacGregor, Barbara</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2014</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>The microbial inhabitants of deep-sea vents are genetically and
                        metabolically diverse, and often make a living at the edge of biological
                        temperature limits. Guaymas Basin, a nascent spreading center in the Gulf of
                        California, provides a unique environment in which to study prokaryotic
                        communities across a range of thermal and geochemical niches. Unlike most
                        vents, Guaymas is blanketed in thick sediments, ranging from 3ºC to 200+ºC
                        within half a meter below the sea floor. Microbial mats, including one
                        nicknamed "Megamat," serve as bull's-eyes for subsurface hydrothermal
                        activity. Here we explore Megamat's subsurface, spanning low-temperature
                        (3º), low-methane (0.3mM) to high-temperature (85º), high-methane (3+ mM)
                        sediments, and the 16S rRNA-based phylogeny of active prokaryotes therein.
                        Pyrosequencing revealed the fewest OTUs yet highest Shannon-Wiener diversity
                        within the hottest sediments. Sequences of Sulfurimonas were nearly
                        ubiquitous, and sequences from the heterotrophic MBGB dominated outside the
                        mat's perimeter. Putative methane cyclers were most abundant within the
                        methane-saturated mat center, including ANME-2c, Methermicoccaceae,
                        Guaymas-specific ANME-1 groups, and a deeply-branching, novel group,
                        "Guaymas Methanomicrobia." The expected Deltaproteobacterial sulfate
                        reducers were not common in this survey; in fact Archaeoglobus and
                        Thermodesulfobacteria sequences were recovered in exponentially higher
                        abundance in the hottest sediments. Major groups were most similar outside
                        of Megamat and at its edge, in contrast with strikingly core-specific
                        communities in central mat samples. The mat's edge appears to be a
                        transition zone hosting sequences found both in the central mat and in bare
                        sediment, while the distinct community assemblages within central Megamat
                        highlight horizontal and vertical variability in Guaymas Basin. Together,
                        these data provide insights into community changes with temperature and
                        substrates at high resolution over small spatial scales.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Master of Science</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Marine biology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Biogeochemistry</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Geobiology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>16S</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>biogeochemistry</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>microbial ecology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Guaymas Basin</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>subsurface microbiology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>hydrothermal vents</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/rr171x313</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:j96020667</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:38:41Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>PRETERM BIRTH PREDICTION AND RECEIPT OF POSTPARTUM CONTRACEPTION AMONG
                        PARTICIPANTS OF NORTH CAROLINA'S PREGNANCY MEDICAL HOME PROGRAM</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Tucker, Christine</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>Gillings School of Global Public Health, Department of Maternal
                        and Child Health</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Menard, M. Kathryn</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Daniels, Julie</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Halpern, Carolyn</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Rowley, Diane</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Herring, Amy</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2014</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>The purpose of this dissertation is to determine which
                        combination of risk factors from Community Care of North Carolina's
                        Pregnancy Medical Home risk screening form is most predictive of preterm
                        birth and to compare receipt of postpartum contraception for women who
                        experienced a recent preterm birth with women who had a term birth. This
                        retrospective cohort includes pregnant Medicaid beneficiaries screened by
                        the program who delivered a live birth in North Carolina between September
                        2011 and September 2012. Data come from Community Care of North Carolina's
                        Case Management Information System, Medicaid claims, and birth certificates.
                        The first paper of the dissertation designed and internally validated a
                        predictive model of preterm birth using variables from the Pregnancy Medical
                        Home risk screen. Logistic regression models and bootstrapping techniques
                        indicated that the optimal combination of risk factors for PTB prediction
                        include non-Hispanic black race, smoking during pregnancy, underweight,
                        multi-fetal gestation, chronic disease (diabetes, hypertension, asthma,
                        renal disease, and other chronic conditions), cervical insufficiency,
                        nulliparity, and previous adverse reproductive outcomes (history of preterm
                        birth, low birth weight baby, fetal death, and second trimester loss).
                        Salient risk factors were identified for subgroups by parity and
                        race/ethnicity including obesity, food insecurity, unsafe or unstable
                        housing, and a short interpregnancy interval. Evaluation of the Pregnancy
                        Medical Home risk screen provides insight to increase its sensitivity and
                        specificity to improve identification of women early in pregnancy at highest
                        risk for preterm birth. The second paper compared the prevalence of
                        contraceptive receipt and effectiveness in Medicaid claims among women with
                        and without a recent preterm birth using logistic and multinomial logistic
                        regression. Contraceptive receipt was 50% (25% for the most effective
                        methods) for women who delivered preterm at 90 days postpartum compared to
                        52% (28% for the most effective methods) among women who delivered full
                        term. Women with a recent preterm birth with more than two children had
                        lower odds of receiving contraception compared to equal parity women who
                        delivered at term (OR = 0.84, 95% CI: 0.74, 0.96). Care management should
                        focus on the provision of effective methods of contraception to women with a
                        recent preterm birth.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Obstetrics</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Epidemiology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Gynaecology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Public health</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Risk Screening</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>North Carolina</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Preterm Birth</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Postpartum Contraception</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Medicaid</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Race/Ethnic Disparities</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/j96020667</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:8c97kq50d</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:40:02Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>From Forgotten to Remembered: The Long Process of School Desegregation
                        in Chapel Hill, North Carolina and Prince Edward County, Virginia</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Waugh, Dwana</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        History</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Filene, Peter G.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2012</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>This dissertation chronicles the history of two black high
                        schools in Chapel Hill, North Carolina, and Prince Edward County, Virginia,
                        during the desegregation process. Both local communities represent important
                        case studies for examining the long and complicated history of school
                        desegregation. While Chapel Hill school officials' reluctant compliance to
                        school desegregation resulted in few black students in predominately white
                        schools a decade after the Brown ruling, Prince Edward County leaders'
                        defiant refusal to accept any desegregation of the public schools resulted
                        in wide-scale closure of the school system for five years. In the late
                        1960s, the two school systems caved in to pressure from the local public and
                        the federal government to desegregate their public schools in appreciable
                        numbers. In the ensuing years, the process of desegregation culminated in
                        shutting down black schools or erasing the heritage and traditions of black
                        schools in Chapel Hill and Prince Edward County. By the late twentieth
                        century, blacks demanded their local communities preserve the legacies of
                        their closed black high schools. Using oral histories and archival sources,
                        I examine how people's memories of desegregation reveal the dynamics of
                        power and race in their local communities. Through interrogating black
                        schoolhouses as "sites of memory," my dissertation argues that southern
                        blacks' activism is both representative of a constant set of racial
                        negotiations over educational power and control and symbolic of a larger
                        movement for racial equity and social justice. The process of school
                        desegregation offered blacks a new language in which to articulate their
                        resistance to inequitable social structures. The commemorative process of
                        refashioning black schools, once sites of black protest and community loss,
                        provides blacks a way in which to ground their frustrations with the
                        contemporary school system and carve out public space in their
                        communities.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>History</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/8c97kq50d</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:vh53wv82z</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:40:14Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Kazakhstan and the 2010 chairmanship of the Organization for Security
                        and Cooperation in Europe: progress toward democracy?</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Mot, Ana Maria Manuela</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Center for Slavic, Eurasian, and
                        East European Studies, Russian, Eurasian and East European
                        Concentration</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Robertson, Graeme</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2011</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>The association of Kazakhstan to the Organization for Security
                        and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), a regional organization with a strong
                        human rights component, could not induce the oil-rich Central Asian country,
                        long since criticized for its poor human rights record, to change its
                        behavior toward sustainable democratic progress. For Kazakhstan, the 2010
                        chairmanship of the OSCE represented a missed opportunity to fulfill its
                        pledges to develop civil and political rights aimed at bringing democratic
                        changes. There are two main reasons for this failure: on the one hand, the
                        lack of institutional capacity of the OSCE in providing an incentive and
                        punishment mechanism to enforce the participating states to fulfill their
                        commitments and on the other hand a combination of external factors and
                        internal conditions in Kazakhstan that prevent democratic
                        development.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/vh53wv82z</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:ff365532n</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:41:52Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Remote Control of Neuronal Signaling in vivo</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Rogan, Sarah</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Medicine, Department of Pharmacology</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Siderovski, David P.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Harden, T. Kendall</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Wetsel, William</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Malanga, C. J.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Roth, Bryan</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2011</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>A significant challenge for neuroscientists is to determine how
                        both electrical and chemical signals affect the activity of cells and
                        circuits and how the nervous system subsequently translates that activity
                        into behavior. Remote, bidirectional manipulation of those signals with high
                        spatiotemporal precision is an ideal approach to addressing that challenge.
                        Recently, neuroscientists have developed a diverse set of tools that permit
                        such experimental manipulation with varying degrees of spatial, temporal,
                        and directional control. These tools use light, peptides, and small
                        molecules to primarily activate ion channels and G protein-coupled receptors
                        (GPCRs) that in turn activate or inhibit neuronal firing. By monitoring the
                        electrophysiological, biochemical, and behavioral effects of such
                        activation/inhibition, researchers can better understand the links between
                        brain activity and behavior. The research in this thesis centers on using a
                        class of designer GPCRs, termed Designer Receptors Exclusively Activated by
                        Designer Drugs (DREADDs), to remotely and non-invasively control the
                        activity of particular neuronal populations. DREADDs are evolved muscarinic
                        receptors that selectively respond to the otherwise inert compound
                        clozapine-N-oxide (CNO) and not to their native ligand, acetylcholine. Using
                        a chemical-genetic approach, I demonstrate that the Gq-coupled DREADD
                        (hM3Dq), which is derived from the human muscarinic M3 receptor, can be used
                        to activate neuronal firing selectively in the cortex and hippocampus of
                        mice expressing hM3Dq. The neuronal activation subsequently results in
                        behavioral and electrophysiological changes. Then, I use those behavioral
                        changes as a readout to examine the underlying neurocircuitry and discuss
                        the findings in the context of psychosis. The tools for remote control of
                        neuronal activity, including DREADDs, differ in the direction of their
                        effect (activation/inhibition, hyperpolarization/depolarization), their
                        onset and offset kinetics (milliseconds/minutes/hours), the degree of
                        spatial resolution they afford, and their invasiveness. While none of these
                        tools is perfect, they each have advantages and disadvantages, which I
                        describe, and they are all still works-in-progress. I conclude with a
                        discussion of the clinical and translational applications of these
                        technologies and provide suggestions for improving upon the existing
                        tools.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Neurosciences</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Pharmacology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/ff365532n</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:f7623c709</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:42:08Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Security first: the response of the Iraqi population to
                        counterinsurgency strategy</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Uthlaut, David A.</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Sociology</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Kurzman, Charles</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2011</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Given the U.S. military's current engagement with insurgencies
                        in Iraq and Afghanistan, it is possible and prudent to test the
                        effectiveness of U.S. counterinsurgency doctrine in practice. This article
                        tests the predictive power of access to essential services, unemployment,
                        perceptions of improved security, insurgent attacks, and demographic
                        characteristics upon Iraqi citizens' confidence in the counterinsurgent
                        forces and the Iraqi insurgency. It also tests the predictive power of
                        confidence in the various counterinsurgent and insurgent forces, as well as
                        the aforementioned variables, upon future attacks. In the first test, survey
                        respondents' perceptions of improved security and their ethno-sectarian
                        community are the most consistent predictors of confidence in
                        counterinsurgent and insurgent forces, while the rest are inconsistent or
                        insignificant predictors. In the second test, survey responses from a
                        specific district were insufficient to consistently predict future attacks
                        in that same district.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/f7623c709</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:gm80hv39h</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:42:20Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Adolescent Alcohol Use and Dating Violence Perpetration: Three Studies
                        Examining Concurrent and Longitudinal Relations Across Grades 8 Through
                        12</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>McNaughton Reyes, Heathe Luz</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>Gillings School of Global Public Health, Department of Health
                        Behavior</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Foshee, Vangie</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>December 2009</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Numerous studies suggest a link between alcohol use and adult
                        partner violence, but research on how this relationship unfolds during
                        adolescence is limited. The three studies comprising this dissertation each
                        used a different theoretical lens to guide an empirical examination of the
                        relations between alcohol use and physical dating violence perpetration
                        using data from a longitudinal study spanning grades 8 through 12. Study one
                        (n=2272) used autoregressive latent curve models to examine several
                        different theoretical models of the linkages between alcohol use and dating
                        violence perpetration over time. Trajectories of alcohol use and dating
                        violence were correlated and this correlation was reduced substantially
                        after adjusting for the effects of common predictors. However, concurrent
                        associations between the two behaviors persisted across nearly all grades.
                        There was no evidence of prospective relations from alcohol use to dating
                        violence or vice-versa. Study two (n=2311) examined the role of heavy
                        alcohol use in the developmental process of desistance from dating violence
                        perpetration. Growth models were used to test the hypotheses that both early
                        and continuing alcohol use would hinder desistance from dating violence
                        during late adolescence. Contrary to expectations, the effects of early
                        alcohol use on dating violence diminished over time. Although the
                        contemporaneous effects of alcohol use on dating violence were significant
                        across most grades, effects weakened during late adolescence and were
                        stronger in the spring than in the fall semesters. Study three (n=2311)
                        examined the hypothesis that increased exposure to violence would strengthen
                        the relationship between heavy alcohol use and dating violence. Growth
                        models were used to examine the main and joint effects of alcohol use and
                        exposure to family, peer, and neighborhood violence on levels of dating
                        violence across grades 8 through 12. Across all grades, the relationship
                        between alcohol use and dating violence was stronger for teens exposed to
                        higher levels of family conflict and friend dating violence. Prevention
                        programs that target risk factors common to both dating violence and alcohol
                        use may reduce involvement in both behaviors. Programs that seek to reduce
                        alcohol-related dating violence should target younger teens and those
                        exposed to family conflict or friend dating violence.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/gm80hv39h</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:rv042t10k</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:42:25Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>MEDIATION DURING INTERNATIONAL CONFLICTS: EVIDENCE FROM SUMNER WELLES’
                        MISSION TO EUROPE IN 1940</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Baily, Spencer</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Political
                        Science</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Moroff, Holger</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Peters, Ingo</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2016</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>The important question that this study attempted to answer is Do
                        diplomatic trips that neutral countries take during wartime influence the
                        conflict? In investigating this question, a trip to Europe taken by U.S.
                        Under Secretary Sumner Welles was inspected. A yardstick was created from
                        the findings of prior literature on mediation. Welles’ trip during the
                        beginning of World War II was then compared to this yardstick. The author
                        found that Welles’ mission was insightful but did not influence European
                        countries. Finally, diplomatic trips taken during wartime do affect the
                        conflict but only if certain tasks are performed by the
                        mediator.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Master of Arts</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>relations</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Mediation</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>International</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Diplomacy</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Conflict Resolution</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Peace Studies</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/rv042t10k</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:05741r876</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:42:34Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Nongovernmental organizations and the World Trade
                        Organization</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Van Liere, Adam Neal</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Political
                        Science</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Oatley, Thomas H.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2010</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Since 1995 over 1,700 different NGOs have found ways to engage
                        the WTO. They have submitted unsolicited amicus briefs and attended
                        ministerial conferences en masse, disrupting the organization and
                        aggravating its membership. They have also submitted over 460 position
                        papers and participated in numerous WTO-sponsored symposia. In spite of
                        these observations, very little is actually known about this overall group
                        of NGOs: what causes do they represent and why do they do what they do? The
                        state-centered emphasis of traditional international relations theory
                        struggles to answer these questions. As an alternative, this dissertation
                        seeks answers by profiling these NGOs and utilizing social movement theory
                        in a multi-level framework to explore their motivations. Are these NGOs
                        responding to the political opportunities at the WTO to defend critical
                        interests, or are they merely using the WTO to help attract additional
                        resources to their cause?</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/05741r876</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:g732d901r</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:42:55Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Engagement of Students with Intellectual and Developmental
                        Disabilities in Postsecondary Education</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Furgang, Emily</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Medicine, College of Arts and Sciences, Department of
                        Allied Health Sciences, Division of Occupational Science and Occupational
                        Therapy</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Humphry, Ruth</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2013</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>This dissertation presents finding s from an ethnographic study
                        of students with intellectual and developmental disabilities (IDD) enrolled
                        in a specialized postsecondary education program at a public university in
                        North Carolina. Specifically, it discusses how 10 students engaged in
                        postsecondary education activities and developed student identities over the
                        course of one academic year. A transactional perspective is used to frame
                        this study holistically, such that the transactions of various factors
                        contributing to the students' occupation and identity development are
                        considered. This research is significant for occupational science because it
                        examines a period of transition that is influential in shaping current and
                        future life occupations. Moreover, it explores the novel occupational
                        experiences of a population that has historically been restricted from
                        engaging in postsecondary education. This study utilized qualitative
                        methods, including semi-structured interviews and participant observation
                        with college students with IDD. Findings address the transactional nature of
                        engagement in postsecondary education and the construction of the students'
                        occupations and identities, while affirming the dialectical relationship of
                        occupation and identity previously described in the occupational science
                        literature. These findings are portrayed through stories of the students'
                        experiences. Further areas for research related to the experiences of
                        college students with IDD engaging in postsecondary education are also
                        discussed.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/g732d901r</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:pr76f353n</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:43:05Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Arsenic Compromises the Alveolocapillary Barrier, Facilitating
                        Bacteremia in a Mouse Pneumonia Model</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Henderson, Michael</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Medicine, Curriculum in Toxicology</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Fry, Rebecca</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Fessler, Michael</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Jaspers, Ilona</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>December 2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>The greatest threat to public health regarding arsenic exposure
                        is consumption of contaminated drinking water. Chronic oral consumption of
                        inorganic arsenic has been linked with respiratory dysfunction as well as
                        immunotoxicity. Here we examined the effects of consuming either of two
                        concentrations of sodium arsenite (250 ppb, 25 ppm) via drinking water in a
                        mouse model of bacterial pneumonia. Arsenic exposure did not alter
                        recruitment of leukocytes to the airway upon bacterial infection, nor
                        pulmonary clearance of bacteria, but was associated with increased
                        dissemination to extrapulmonary tissues. Mice exposed to arsenic had intact
                        bloodstream killing of bacteria, suggesting that the increased
                        extrapulmonary bacterial burden in lung-infected mice derived from increased
                        escape from the lung. Analysis of early events in lung-infected mice
                        revealed that arsenic led to accelerated escape of bacteria from the
                        alveoli, providing new evidence that chronic exposure to
                        arsenic-contaminated drinking water disrupts the architecture of the
                        alveoli, permitting pathogen escape into the bloodstream.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Master of Science</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Immunology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Microbiology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Toxicology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>bacteremia</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>klebsiella</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>alveolar</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Arsenic</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>dissemination</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>lung</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Masters Thesis</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/pr76f353n</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:rf55z782m</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:43:25Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>Mediation of the effects of obesity on coronary heart disease in a
                        bi-ethnic cohort: the Atherosclerosis Risk in Communities (ARIC)
                        Study</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>McClain, Jill E.</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>Gillings School of Global Public Health, Department of
                        Nutrition</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Stevens, June Sheppa</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:date>December 2009</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Excess adiposity is associated with physiologic risk factors for
                        coronary heart disease (CHD), including dyslipidemia, high blood pressure
                        and insulin resistance, however few studies have analyzed mediation of the
                        obesity-CHD relationship by individual physiologic risk factors. Mediation
                        can be examined using structural equation modeling (SEM), which has several
                        advantages over standard regression for analyses of mediation, including
                        significance-testing of the individual indirect (mediated) effects. We used
                        data from the Atherosclerosis Risk in Communities (ARIC) Study, a
                        longitudinal cohort of 15,792 African American and White adults aged 45-64
                        years at baseline (1987-1989) and followed through 2005, to examine
                        mediation of the effects of body mass index (BMI) on CHD hazard. Physiologic
                        risk factors examined included total and high density lipoprotein (HDL)
                        cholesterol, triglycerides, systolic and diastolic blood pressure (SBP, DBP)
                        and insulin resistance. The overall effect of BMI on CHD was curved, with a
                        steeper slope at lower compared to higher BMI levels. Mediated effects of
                        BMI on CHD tended to be strongest through HDL cholesterol and insulin
                        resistance. Mediation was more moderate through total cholesterol and SBP,
                        and was null through DBP and triglycerides. In models that included all 6
                        hypothesized mediators, BMI was not directly associated with CHD. We found
                        no differences in mediation by race or gender. Because antihypertensive
                        medication use is highly prevalent in this cohort (31% at baseline), we
                        explored the impact of medication use on our analyses involving blood
                        pressure. The associations of BMI with blood pressure and with CHD were
                        markedly attenuated in participants taking antihypertensive medication
                        compared to participants not taking antihypertensive medications, though the
                        association of blood pressure with CHD was not different between the two
                        groups. When associations of BMI with SBP and DBP were compared in the same
                        individuals before and after initiating treatment with antihypertensive
                        medications, no differences were found. Overall, these results highlight the
                        complexity of analyses of blood pressure in persons being treated with
                        antihypertensive medication and underscore the importance of traditional
                        physiologic risk factors, particularly HDL cholesterol and insulin
                        resistance, as mediators of the effect of obesity on CHD.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/rf55z782m</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:zc77sq19f</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:43:33Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>MACBETH: management of avatar conflict by employment of a technique
                        hybrid</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Burns, Eric M.</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>College of Arts and Sciences, Department of Computer
                        Science</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Brooks, Frederick P.</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>May 2007</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Since virtual objects do not prevent users from penetrating
                        them, a virtual environment user may place his real hand inside a virtual
                        object. If the virtual environment system prevents the user's hand avatar
                        from penetrating the object, the hand avatar must be placed somewhere other
                        than the user's real hand position. I propose a technique, named MACBETH
                        (Management of Avatar Conflict By Employment of a Technique Hybrid) for
                        managing the position of a user's hand avatar in a natural manner after it
                        has been separated from the user's real hand due to collision with a virtual
                        object. This technique balances visual/proprioceptive discrepancy in
                        position and velocity by choosing each so that they are equally detectable.
                        To gather the necessary information to implement MACBETH, I performed user
                        studies to determine users' detection thresholds for visual/proprioceptive
                        discrepancy in hand position and velocity. I then ran a user study to
                        evaluate MACBETH against two other techniques for managing the hand avatar
                        position: the rubber-band and incremental-motion techniques. Users rated
                        MACBETH as more natural than the other techniques and preferred MACBETH over
                        both. Users performed better on a hand navigation task with MACBETH than
                        with the incremental-motion technique and performed equally well as with the
                        rubber-band technique.</dc:description>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/zc77sq19f</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>ir.lib.unc.edu:x633f108q</identifier>
                <datestamp>2019-04-05T18:44:31Z</datestamp>
                <setSpec>ETD</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>The Role of Curcumin in Modulating Colonic Microbiota During Colitis
                        and Colon Cancer Prevention</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>McFadden, Rita-Marie</dc:creator>
                    <dc:contributor>School of Dentistry</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Arnold, Roland</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Barros, Silvana</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Kiela, Pawel</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Phillips, Ceib</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:contributor>Jobin, Christian</dc:contributor>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:publisher>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Graduate
                        School</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>August 2014</dc:date>
                    <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
                    <dc:description>Background: Inflammatory bowel diseases (IBD) are a major risk
                        factor for colon cancer. Intestinal microbiota have been identified as the
                        target of inflammation that affects the progression of colitis-associated
                        colorectal cancer (CAC). With diet being a key determinant of the gut
                        microbial ecology, dietary interventions are an attractive avenue for the
                        prevention of CAC. Curcumin is the most active constituent of the ground
                        rhizome of the Curcuma Longa plant, which has been demonstrated to have
                        anti-inflammatory, anti-oxidative, pro-apoptotic and anti-proliferative
                        properties. However, the exact role of curcumin in colon cancer prevention
                        and modulation of the microbial communities are yet to be determined.
                        Methods: A mouse model of CAC was utilized in which Il10-/- mice on 129/SvEv
                        background develop progressive colitis. On the starting day, WT or Il10-/-
                        mice received a 100µL i.p. injection of 10mg/kg body weight of azoxymethane
                        (AOM) or sterile saline (continued once a week for six weeks total) and were
                        started on one of the following curcumin-supplemented diets: 0%, 0.05%, 0.1%
                        or 0.5%. Mice were monitored for weight loss, rectal prolapse, rectal
                        bleeding, and stool consistency. Stools were collected every four weeks for
                        microbial analysis (Illumina 16S rRNA profiling). At the conclusion of the
                        study, mice were assessed for tumor burden, colonic histopathology and
                        colonic cytokine profile. Results: Curcumin-supplemented diets increased
                        survival, decreased colon weight/length ratios and reduced tumor burden in a
                        dose-dependent manner. Distal colon histopathology in Il10-/- mice exposed
                        to AOM with the 0.5% curcumin diet demonstrated a reduction of inflammation
                        score and a reduction in the frequency of adenocarcinoma detection. Curcumin
                        altered the microbial ecology in the gut of Il10-/- mice fed the 0.5%
                        curcumin diet. DIfferences in microbial diversity were observed in mice with
                        tumors vs. without, as well as in mice that had spontaneous vs. AOM-induced
                        tumors. Conclusions: In a dose-dependent manner, dietary curcumin results in
                        a less severe presentation of colitis, in a reduced risk of progression to
                        CRC upon exposure to AOM and a more diverse colonic microbial ecology in the
                        Il10-/- mice. This suggests that curcumin functions as an effective agent
                        for restoring healthy gut homeostasis.</dc:description>
                    <dc:description>Doctor of Philosophy</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Dentistry</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Immunology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Microbiology</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>microbiota</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>colon</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>16S rRNA</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>curcumin</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>cancer</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>diet</dc:subject>
                    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
                    <dc:type>Dissertation</dc:type>
                    <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
                    <dc:identifier>https://ir.lib.unc.edu/concern/dissertations/x633f108q</dc:identifier>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
        <resumptionToken completeListSize="9183">oai_dc.s(admin
            set:Dissertations).f(2019-04-01T13:51:49Z).u(2019-05-28T12:40:53Z).t(9183):50</resumptionToken>
    </ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
